<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Catalyst COVID</title>
    <link>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Catalyst COVID</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://catalyst-covid.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/introduction/</guid>
      <description>The Introduction’s Introduction Welcome to Catalyst COVID, a series of articles showcasing how societies around the world are turning to mass surveillance for national security, interpersonal trust, and optimizing their economies in the time of a global pandemic.
Background &amp;amp; Stereotypes The first working implementation of a mass surveillance system as we stereotypically think about today was revealed to the world in 2013 when Edward Snowden released classified documents detailing the United States National Security Agency’s program to gather and record data on nearly all US citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/glossary/</guid>
      <description>Steven Nock (credentials) Steven Nock was a professor of sociology whose research and writings centered around the role of family and marriage in society.
While not necessarily included in the canon of academic surveillance studies, in his article &amp;ldquo;Too Much Privacy?&amp;rdquo; in the Journal of Family Issues, Nock presents a compelling and somewhat counterintuitive take on surveillance. He asserts that, contrary to common thought, &amp;ldquo;Americans enjoy more privacy today than their ancestors did&amp;rdquo; and surveillance is the price we pay for that privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Surveillance</title>
      <link>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/seeking-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/seeking-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>Meet the audio interview!   Introduction I began this year and entered my formal study of surveillance culture with an open mind and many preconceived notions about what surveillance is, how it works, who uses it, and for what means. I carried a vague understanding that surveillance had something to do with power, but the specifics remained unarticulated. To me, surveillance came from &amp;ldquo;the Man”—the boss, the government, the police, the military, the big tech corporations, et cetera.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The World Wide COVID-19 Response</title>
      <link>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/world-wind-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/world-wind-response/</guid>
      <description>Intro: What is it that we mean when we say surveillance? The word itself evokes thoughts of George Orwell and Big Brother, but it’s easy to convince ourselves that we don’t always think of surveillance so negatively. What of the shopkeeper who wishes to reduce theft with security cameras? The taxi driver whose dash camera prevents insurance fraud? Is not the daycare worker who watches over a group of young children necessarily performing surveillance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surveillance Capitalism in a COVID-19 World</title>
      <link>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/capitalism-covid-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/capitalism-covid-surveillance/</guid>
      <description>Consumers in Isolation The COVID-19 pandemic has brought about the degradation of social institutions. Restaurants, movie theaters, and gyms lie abandoned, cars no longer fill the street. Social institutions where humans congregated and interacted are now gone. These stay-at-home orders issued by the government and encouraged by the public have relegated the vast majority of American citizens to their homes.
Reports show that this pattern is here to stay. Georgia, one of the first states to allow businesses to reopen, found that consumer willingness to visit physical locations did not improve significantly, even after a massive push to reopen businesses out of economic fears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Musical Inspiration</title>
      <link>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/a-musical-inspiration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/post/a-musical-inspiration/</guid>
      <description>The Song    Description Who’s There is a song whose instrumental parts were written by Allen El and lyrical and vocal parts written by Italian singer from the band Destination 511, Lorenzo. It showcases an artistic piece created during the quarintinte of covid 19. The song reflects how covid 19 applies to people globally, and shows the experience of a singer in a country that has gotten a lot of attention during covid 19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://catalyst-covid.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus. Donec sed odio dui.
Donec sed odio dui. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue. Praesent commodo cursus magna, vel scelerisque nisl consectetur et.
Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>